# **Adrian Salgado**

# **Software Engineer**

 $\times\times\times\times\times$ 

hola@lasfi.to

YouTube.com/@lasfito

GitHub.com/lasfito

Software Engineer with 3+ years of experience in web development (frontend / backend) and mobile development. Proficient in JavaScript, TypeScript, Node, React, and React Native. Currently learning Go, working on building an indie SaaS, and creating Spanish dev tutorials on YouTube.

#### Experience -

#### **Software Engineer II**

Honeywell

May 2022 - Feb 2023

- Participated in the building of an enterprise micro-frontend SPA through federated modules.
- Devised and conducted test plans to ensure 95%+ code coverage through unit testing.
- Actively participating in sprint grooming, planning & code review with a 100% say-do ratio.

Git, JavaScript, Jest, Jira, React, Serverless, Redux, RTK Query, StoryBook, Styled Components, Tailwind, TypeScript.

## **Software Engineer**

LATAVAL

Nov 2021 - April 2022

- Lead the architecture and development of a mobile App (React Native) with over 10k MAU.
- Set up production-facing REST API endpoints to handle a peak of 1,000 requests per second.
- Developed an internal CMS by leveraging Google Cloud Platform and CI/CD pipelines.

AWS, CSS3, Docker, Expo, Express.js, Google Cloud, Linux, Next.js, Node.js, React.js, React Native, Remix, Strapi.

Web Developer Waldo's Co

Aug 2021 - Oct 2021

Optimized the company's e-commerce loading speed by 3s and improved the UI responsiveness. CSS, Firebase, Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager, HTML5, JavaScript, Liquid, NoSQL, Shopify, React.

Web Developer

7iete Studio

July 2020 - June 2021

- Created performant (1s load) websites by leveraging SSR/SSG UI frameworks through Jamstack.
- Developed cross-platform (Android/iOS) apps with great UX as measured by 27% user retention.
- Enhanced an internal dashboard for dataviz by 25% as measured by loading performance.

Express, Firebase, Gatsby, GraphQL, GitHub, MUI, Netlify, Next, Node, OOP, PWA, React, React Native, Sass, WordPress.

Webmaster

**CEMERI** 

Sept 2019 - July 2020

- Designed and optimized the SEO architecture with monthly increments of 15% impressions.
- Built an academic search engine through Google API that was in use by over 10K students.
- Designed an internal tool for map creation (d3.js) which boosted publishing rate by 33%.

CSS, JavaScript, Google Analytics, Google Search Console, Google Tag Manager, HTML, XML, Wordpress.

#### Projects -

### **Content Creation** Watch »

Sept 2021 - Current

Web development tutorials on YouTube. Currently at 220k views & 3k subscribers.

Xolo SEO Visit »

Jan 2023 - Current

A SaaS that leverages NLP/AI to help you reach the 1st page of Google Results.

- Set up a microservice app infrastructure through dockerization and deployment on the cloud.
- Modeled the database, built the current POC and layed out an architectural plan for future work. FastAPI, Firebase, GCP, HuggingFace, Playwright, PostgreSQL, Prisma, Python, Railway, React, Remix, SQL.

**Education** -

**Language Certificates:** C1 English by IELTS O A2 Russian by PSU O N5 Japanese by JLPT. **BA International Relations** at UNAM - Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México. 2015 - 2019

Mechatronics Engineering (Dropout) at Tecnológico de Monterrey.

2013 - 2015